一 二 三 一 二 三
One two three… One two three…
一 二 三
One two three…
一 二 三 一 二 三 转圈儿
One two three… One two three… Turn…
陛下 转圈儿
Lord, turn!
王后陛下 并非如此 不 不 不
My Lady! This way! No, no, no, no, no, no.
我来演示给您看
I will show you.
要这样 您看到了吗
Comme sa! You see?
要风姿高雅
Elegant.
举手投足雍容雅贵
Everything is elegant.
要清妙纤美
Beautiful!
投足举手非雅即美
Everything that is not elegant must be beautiful.
陛下
Your Majesty.
许久未曾召见你 抱歉
I haven't seen you for a good while. I'm sorry.
我不明所以
I did not know the reason for it.
亦无人告之
No one told me.
我身体抱恙
I was unwell.
但现已无大碍
But now I am better.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
我相信吾体欠安之时 你也寻得乐趣
I trust you found something to amuse yourself.
聊以自娱吧
while I was away?
我对陛下朝思暮想 魂牵梦萦
I missed Your Majesty so much.
他们可曾将礼物送达
I hope they gave you my gifts.
礼物怎可抵陛下
Your gifts are not you.
萨里大人
My Lord Surrey.
陛下
Majesty.
汝乃吾妻之血亲
You are a blood relative of my wife.
因此 并鉴于你在法国位尊显贵
For that reason, and because you so distinguished yourself in France,
我决定授予你嘉德骑士勋位
I've decided to make you a Knight of the Order of the Garter.
这可合你心意
Does it please you?
陛下 在下感激不尽
I am deeply grateful, Your Majesty.
萨里大人 退下吧
My Lord Surrey.
遵旨
Majesty.
我要给你样东西
Ah, I have something for you.
谢谢您 真是美丽绝伦
Thank you. It's beautiful.
你也是如此
So are you.
明日我要外出一段时日
I am going away tomorrow, for a few days.
但今晚我要你侍寝
But tonight I will visit to your bedchamber.
因为若你能喜结珠胎
For nothing would please me more.
我将欣喜至极
than for you to conceive my child.
陛下 早安
Your Majesty, good morning.
主教大人
My Lord Bishop.
陛下 这些人穷困潦倒 身患痼疾
Your Majesty, these poor, suffering subjects,
他们乞哀告怜 已求得获准
they have begged leave to receive.
接受陛下恩赐
Your Majesty's gift of grace.
陛下可否将尊手置于他们额头之上
So if Your Majesty might consent to lay your hands upon them?
求陛下施恩 求您了 陛下
Your Majesty. Please. Please. Your Majesty.
籍上帝恩典 吾命汝病痊愈
By the Grace of God, I command you to be healed.
籍上帝恩典
By the Grace of God,
吾命汝病痊愈
I command you to be healed.
陛下 求您施恩
Please, Your Majesty.
籍上帝恩典 吾赐汝病痊愈
By the Grace of God, I command you to be healed.
还有我 陛下 请求您
Please, Your Majesty. Please.
籍上帝恩典 吾赐汝病痊愈
By the Grace of God, I command you to be healed.
谢陛下
Your Majesty. Your Majesty.
籍上帝恩典
By the Grace of God,
吾赐汝病痊愈
I command you to be healed.
上帝保佑您 陛下 谢陛下恩典
God bless you, Your Majesty. Thank you, Your Majesty.
谢陛下恩典
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
谢陛下恩典 谢陛下恩典
Oh, thank you, Your Majesty. Thank you, Your Majesty.
Oh, thank you, Your Majesty. Thank you. Oh, thank you.
谢陛下恩典
Thank you, Your Majesty!
上帝保佑 陛下万福
God bless you, Your Majesty!
（希佛堡 克里维斯的安之宅邸）
很好 小姐 非常精彩
Bravo, my Lady. Bravo!
- 陛下 - 陛下
- Your Majesty. - Majesty.
陛下
Your Majesty.
我的出现 算是惊喜吗
Did I surprise you?
那就好
Good.
- 伊丽莎白公主 - 陛下
- Lady Elizabeth. - Your Grace.
我有礼物送你
I have a gift for you.
你的拉丁语学得如何
How is your Latin?
我乐在其中 谢谢关心 陛下
I enjoy learning it, thank you, Your Majesty.
您为我指派的家教 格林代尔先生
Mr Grindle, the tutor you gave me,
他是位一流的导师
is an excellent teacher.
此书为罗马历史学家塔西佗所著
This book is by the Roman historian Tacitus.
也许你现在读来尚有难度
Now you may find it difficult to read.
但值得花费精力一阅
but the effort will be worthwhile.
人若胸无点墨 生命便毫无意义
For without knowledge, life is not worth having.
非常感谢您 陛下
Thank you so much, Your Majesty.
我一直心怀感激
I am very grateful.
每晚都感谢上帝赐您健康之躯
and thank God every night for your good health.
并坚信您会成为我们的明君 慈父
and trust you will be our good King, and father,
福泽千秋
a long time.
女士
Madam.
我是来用晚膳的
I have come for supper.
希望不会给您带来不便
I hope that doesn't inconvenience you.
我想食品间里定有可供您享用之物 陛下
I think we may find something in the larder, Your Majesty.
如此甚好
Good.
您正式的授勋仪式
Your formal installation into the Order.
不日便会举行 萨里大人
will take place soon, my Lord Surrey.
陛下赐福在下为您打点一切
The King's grace has commanded me to prepare you for the event,
当然 我也非常乐意如此
which I am happy and willing to do.
我确信阁下深知
I am sure your lordship is aware of the great significance.
嘉德勋位对陛下而言意义非凡
attached to the Order by His Majesty and the great honor.
受此隆恩 无上荣光
that he conveys upon you by electing you to it.
如您所知 只有国王陛下
As you know, the Order comprises of twenty-five.
和二十五名贵族 骑士才能获此殊荣
noble and valiant knights and their sovereign.
嘉德勋位是英格兰的至高荣誉
There is no greater honor in England.
大人何须班门弄斧
Your lordship has no need to sell the Order to me.
您多久前受此勋位
How long have you belonged to the Order?
今年年初
I was elected earlier this year.
不过几个月而已
A few months, oh.
我父亲和家族四代
My father and four generations of my family.
早已获得此项荣誉
have already belonged to it.
我们用餐吧
Shall we eat?
你猜陛下是去哪了
Where do you suppose the King has gone?
我不知道 陛下
I don't know, Your Majesty.
据说明天有满月
They tell me there's a full moon tomorrow.
我们也该狂野一番
and we shall all behave like lunatics.
对有些人而言 月亮代表着爱
For some, the moon is the planet of love.
我想再见他
I want to see him again.
如您所愿
As you wish.
何不让我将他带至我的房间
Perhaps I could bring him to my room.
由我在外守候 防止外人闯入
Then I could wait outside, in case anyone should come.
在下只求陛下千万小心
I only urge Your Majesty to be careful when you…
小心什么 罗彻福德夫人
What, Lady Rochford?
你以为我不知如何与人偷情
Don't you think I know how to meddle with a man.
而不令自己怀孕吗
without conceiving a child?
陛下当为您的女儿们自豪
Your Majesty should be proud of your daughters.
两个都是
Both of them.
真是虎父无犬女
They do you a great credit.
玛丽小姐为人严谨 冰雪聪明
The Lady Mary is very serious and religious but very clever.
如其他女性一般 她总是表现得大智若愚
like some women, she likes to hide her intelligence.
而伊丽莎白小姐 她的智慧光彩夺目
But the Lady Elizabeth, she cannot hide her intelligence.
她会成为一位伟大的女性
She will be a great lady, I think…
愿上帝遂我心意
if God so wills it.
有样东西 我想还给陛下
I have something which I should like to return to Your Majesty.
我的婚戒
My wedding ring.
我愿您将它打碎
I should like you to break it into pieces,
因为它已毫无价值
as a thing of no value.
亲爱的凯瑟琳
Katherine? Sweetheart?
我在 托马斯
Yes, Thomas.
你喜欢我们如此幽会吗
Do you like our meeting like this?
当然
Yes.
你可爱我
Do you love me yet?
如何证明汝之心意
Let me perceive by some token that you love me.
一亲芳泽吗
Shall I kiss you?
亲爱的凯瑟琳 芳泽已摘
We have kissed before, Katherine sweet.
不足以表明心意
It does not mean that you love me.
那吾该如何是好
What else can I show you?
萨里伯爵大人
My Lord Surrey,
吾现授予你嘉德骑士勋位
I am commanded now to invest you with the Garter,
此供你于授勋仪式上佩戴
for you to wear at your installation.
[古英语]心怀叵测者必自取其辱
"Honni soit qui mal y pense." Evil be to him who evil thinks.
大人
Sir.
吾等为嘉德骑士
The most friendly Companions of this Order,
至善的同道中士
denominated from the Garter,
在此向你 吾兄 吾友 吾士
have admitted you, their friend, brother, and companion,
虔诚宣誓 赐汝嘉德荣光
in faithful testimony of which they impart and give you.
望汝不负天意
the Garter, which God grant that you, deservedly receiving it,
实至荣归
may rightly wear and use to the Glory of God.
谢谢 吾友
Thank you, my friends,
吾兄
brothers,
同伴
and companions.
大人
Your Grace.
你可知我一直对你心存感激
You know I am very grateful to you.
顺从接受你我婚姻的取消
for raising no objection to the annulment of our marriage.
出于我对女人的了解 令我颇感意外
It runs rather counter to my experience of women.
陛下 臣妾一片真心
Your Majesty, I can truly say.
只望陛下诸事天行顺意
that I wish in all things to please you as my Lord,
以回报陛下的大恩大德
to bear testament to your good treatment of me,
也愿留在这片心有眷恋的土地
and to stay in this country that I already love as my own.
你知道法国大使如何描述你吗
Do you know what the French Ambassador wrote about you?
我们拦下了他的信件
We intercepted his letter.
他说英国人民对我们离婚深表遗憾
He said that our people much regretted our divorce,
虽历时很短 你已赢得爱戴
and that in a short time you had won their love,
人民将你誉为最仁慈可人
and that they esteemed you as one of the most sweet,
善良和蔼的王后
gracious, and humane queens they had ever had.
你现在已另有新后
You have another queen now.
是的
Yes.
我喜欢她
I like her.
无可置疑的美貌
She is beautiful, of course.
年轻而充满活力 你一定对她好生仰慕
And very young. Full of life. You must adore her.
陛下
My Lady!
My Lady…
你已尽职
You did your duty.
他实在教人忍无可忍
He's insufferable.
狂妄自大 目中无人
He thinks us all his inferiors.
居然推他的亲属为后
Unfortunately, we did him the great favor.
瞧我们干得好事
of making a member of his family the Queen.
事在人为
What is made can sometimes be unmade-like a bed.
怎么个为法 国王爱她如痴如狂
What chance is there? The King is besotted by her.
- 众人皆知 - 谁知道呢
- Everyone knows that. - That may change.
她不过是个天真无知的小傻瓜
She seems to me nothing but a frivolous and stupid girl.
不管怎样
In any case,
我要你煞煞那个不可一世的伯爵的威风
I want you to teach the Earl a lesson in humility.
竟敢称我为狼女
I will be called a she-wolf.
真是大胆 高贵如你我家族
by no man, nor should you allow.
也绝不应容忍他人的肆意恶意中伤
the slanders against our family to go unpunished.
自然 我那亲爱的丈夫
Surely, my dear husband,
你也可以暗中安排一些天灾人祸
you could arrange for some misfortune to befall him?
好啊 我的朋友们
Hello, my friends!
老天爷
Jesus Christ!
算不上
Not quite!
如你所见 我已被授予英格兰
As you see, I have been received into the most noble,
最至高无上的贵族荣誉
most prestigious Order of the Garter.
嘉德勋位在此
And here indeed is the garter! "Honni soit qui mal y pense."
居心叵测者必自取其辱
Evil to him who evil thinks!
金字良言 万分同意
It's a good motto. I agree with it.
快上酒
Ale, please!
嘉德勋位重任在身
My responsibilities to the Order.
致使我口渴难忍啊
have already made me dreadfully thirsty.
- 好极了 大人 - 多谢
- Very fine, my Lord! - Thank you.
大人 您究竟是如何承担得起这些
How in God's name did you afford all this, my Lord?
我常常身无分文 但总是财运不断
I have often had no money, but I have never been poor.
翠花 你想不想体验一下
Wench! How would you like to suck the cock of a man.
嘉德骑士的神秘利器
who's a member of the Order of the Garter?
你的朋友怎么说
What would your friends say?
不要听风就是雨
They would tell me not to swallow stories like that.
你的手
Your hand!
是如此…
It is…
单薄苍白
all naked.
如此一来 增色不少
There, there, there. It is dressed.
谢了 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
快过来
Come here.
再上美酒 朋友们 不醉不休
More ale. Drink up, my friend. Drink up.
大人们 巡游北方的计划搁置已久
My Lords, we must before long agree.
我们得尽早筹划
on these plans for our much-delayed progress to the North.
随行大批随从 配备侍卫护送
We shall take a large retinue, including men-at-arms,
鉴于我们的目标地
since we mean especially to visit those parts.
前不久刚刚起义造反
of our realm which, not long ago,
悖逆他们无上的国王
raise up and techagainst us.
而这次我希望那里的愚民
However, this time we expect the people,
能够拜我国恩 归顺臣服
being pardoned by our grace, to make further submissions.
弃恶从善 迷途知返
in acknowledgments of their past depravities.
王后陛下
My Lady.
我们还意邀苏格兰国王 詹姆斯
It is also our intention to invite James, King of Scots,
于九月与我们在约克郡会面
to meet with us at York in September.
陛下
Your Majesty.
国王陛下正在开会呢
The King's in Council!
将运送上等挂毯和餐具事宜安排妥当
Arrange for the conveyance of our best tapestries and plates.
遵命 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty…
很抱歉 陛下
I apologize, Your Majesty.
过来
Come.
- 凯瑟琳 你太无礼… - 我的经期推迟了
- Katherine, you silly… - I have missed my bleeding.
我想我是怀孕了
I believe I am with child.
我最亲爱的心肝…
My sweet sweetheart…
还请陛下恕罪 刚才惹您生气了
I had to tell Your Majesty. I am sorry I made you angry.
我没有生气 我怎会生你的气呢 决不会
I'm not angry. How could I be any bit angry? God forbid.
凯瑟琳 听我说 请听我说
Katherine, listen to me, listen to me. Listen to me.
亲爱的宝贝 为了我们的孩子
For the sake of our child, please, girl,
不要过度兴奋 还是回房休息去吧
don't excite yourself. Go and lay down.
保养好身子 我很快便会去看望你
Rest, and I will come and see you very, very soon.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
去吧
Go.
我美丽娇艳的王后 去吧
My beautiful young Queen. Go.
我父王近来可好
How is my father?
回禀公主 国王陛下身疾已愈
The King, having recovered from his recent illness,
近来气色甚佳
seems in much better humor, my Lady.
陛下正在筹划巡游
He is planning to make a progress.
北部疆域
to the North of England.
那边局势动荡 事端层出不穷
A great deal of work is already instigated.
听说绣工们使用教士的长袍
They say that embroiderers are working on furniture.
和从教堂剥取的饰物来装饰家具
and tapestries using copes and ornaments.
并绣制挂毯
stripped from the churches, alas.
歇息一下吧
Excellency.
谢谢 公主
Thank you, Madam.
还有另外一个原因使陛下心舒体适
There is another reason why the King's humor is improved.
风传王后陛下已喜怀龙种
There are rumors. The Queen is thought to be with child.
如她果真能产下一位约克公爵
I'm sure His Majesty would be overjoyed.
相信陛下定会喜出望外
if she produced a Duke of York.
从另一方面说
On the other hand,
如她未能孕产 那么继位的问题
if she does not, then the succession may,
可能会变得玄机难卜
in fact, remain an open question.
此话怎讲
What do you mean?
爱德华理应是第一顺位继承人吧
Surely Edward is first in line? Who could doubt it?
玛丽公主
Lady Mary,
朝中要臣告与我说
certain important people at court have told me.
他们一直对爱德华王子的母亲
they feel a "Scruple" Of conscience.
简王后抱有迟疑态度 因她不像您的母亲
over the fact that Prince Edward's mother,
凯塞琳王后那般名正言顺
Queen Jane, was never ever formally crowned,
她从未被正式加冕过
unlike your own mother, Queen Catherine.
因此有传言称 陛下有意在约克郡
So the rumor also goes, that the King intends to crown.
为新王后加冕 此后如她果真孕续龙脉
his new Queen at York, so if she has a son.
其子铁定无疑会成为王位的继承人
no one can question his legitimacy or right to the throne.
但是 如果她未能孕产皇子的话…
But if she does not have a son…
没错 那样一来您便更有把握问鼎王位
Exactly. It would strengthen your own claim to the crown.
那些朝中要臣还跟我说
Which is why these certain people at court have assured me.
他们日夜企盼 不仅为了倒覆
how they pray, pray, not only for the overthrow.
如赫福德之流的改革派 更是祈望
of vile reformers like Hertford, but for the day and the hour.
有朝一日 您可登临王位 母仪天下
that Your Grace succeeds to the throne.
但顺天意 大人
Only if God wills it, Excellency.
但顺天意
Only if God wills it.
天意已决 玛丽公主
But He must will it, Lady Mary.
如今社稷局艰 隐忧惶存 长此以往 国将不国
For how else will this country ever be restored to obedience.
试问此刻还有谁能力挽危澜 安顺民心
and to faith? Otherwise, as things are,
重树帝国威信
it will go to the devil.
再和我说说这次出行
Tell me more about the progress.
我们要到哪里去
Where shall we go?
先去往赫福德
First to Hatfield,
后经邓斯特布尔 安特希尔和格拉夫顿
then to Dunstable, Ampthill, and Grafton,
一路飞鹰走犬 好不快活
hunting and hawking along the way.
然后去斯坦福 再及林肯
Then to Stamford, and then Lincoln,
最后是波士顿和约克郡
and so on to Boston and Yorkshire.
此番出行 一路定会有诸多庆典及盛宴
And you'll have to have plenty of new dresses made,
你要备足新衣 华艳出席
for there will be many great occasions and banquets along the way,
众人皆会为你的瑰丽而倾倒
and great crowds will come to see your magnificence.
我太兴奋了 所有一切都如同一场
I'm so excited. All of this seems to me.
我只愿长眠不愿醒来的佳梦
still like a dream, from which I hope never to wake!
今晚您要来临幸与我吗
Will you come to my bedchamber tonight?
不 亲爱的 如今你身怀有孕
No, sweetheart. It's too dangerous.
这样太危险了
not while you're with child.
怎么了 你不是已怀有我的血脉了吗
What's the matter? You are with child?
我搞错了
I was mistaken.
我 我弄错了
I… I miss…
陛下
My Lady?
卡尔佩珀大人
Master Culpepper,
我多想委身于你
I heartily recommend me unto you…
又不知君心何意
Praying you send me word how that you do.
若你此时在我身旁
I would you were with me now that you might.
便知我柔肠寸断 泣难下笔
see what pain I take in writing to you.
「我听闻你抱恙在身 恨不得胁下生翼
"I heard that you were sick. And never longed so much.
不顾一切见到你
"for anything as to see you.
每每想起你不能常伴左右 我便心碎不已「
It makes my heart die to think I can't always be in your company."
每每想起
It makes my heart die.
你不能常伴左右 我便心碎不已
to think I cannot always be in your company. Yours…
你至死不渝的凯瑟琳
Yours as long as life endures, Katherine.
那不是她的错 她太年轻了
It's not her fault. She's so young.
不 就是她的错
No. That is her fault.
你水平不错
You play well.
我记得你过去可不怎么会玩
You didn't used to, I remember.
我过去也不会喝酒 不懂乐器
And I never used to drink wine, or play music.
而现在我什么都会
Now I do all those things…
而且很喜欢 我自由自在 想做就做
and I like to do it. I am free, and I like to do it.
今夜能与你共寝吗
May I come to your bed tonight?
我在这儿呢 可不愿见你心碎
I'm here now. I don't want your heart to die.
你是如此可爱
You feel so sweet.
迷人的小傻瓜
My sweet little fool.
我爱你
I love you.
你绝不能… 明白吗
You mustn't… you know?
不会的
I won't.
我保证
I promise.
陛下
Your Majesty,
布莱恩女士求见
Lady Bryan.
陛下 大人
Your Majesty. My Lord.
您的儿子 爱德华王子在此
Here is your son, Prince Edward.
陛下 叔父
Your Majesty. Uncle.
殿下
Your Grace.
爱德华
Edward.
他们可有精心照料你
I trust you are well looked after.
待你和善可亲
and everybody is kind to you.
是的 陛下
Yes, sir.
我有礼物送你
I have a gift for you.
谢谢 陛下
Thank you, Your Majesty.
我要离开伦敦数日
I have to go away from London for a while.
不过你叔父留在这里
But your uncle will stay here.
务必照顾好他 布莱恩女士
He is to be kept warm and well at Windsor, Lady Bryan.
万一你生病了 但愿不会
And if, heaven forbid, you should fall ill,
就给他用这个 这是我的特效药
dose him with this. It's my own concoction.
你身上有你母亲的影子
I can see your mother in you.
知道她是谁吗
Do you know who she was?
这就是她
This is her.
这是她的顶针
And this is her thimble.
真是好孩子
You're a good boy.
你的剑 殿下
Your sword, sir.
陛下
Your Majesty.
王后陛下 国王驾到
My Lady, the King is here.
凯瑟琳 我是来通知你
Katherine, I've come to tell you that we are.
两日内我们即启程前往白厅
leaving Whitehall in two days time.
相信你已准备妥当
I trust you are prepared.
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
忘了告诉你
Oh, I've also come to tell you,
玛丽公主与我们同行
the Lady Mary will be accompanying us.
为什么
Why?
她一定要去吗
Must she come?
显然你不清楚状况
Obviously you don't understand.
玛丽在北部深受爱戴
Mary is a much-loved figure in the North,
于我们此行的目的大有裨益
where we mean to impress our subjects.
此事已决 你无权过问
The decision has nothing to do with you.
我很抱歉没有怀上龙种
I'm sorry I was not with child.
我肯定能怀上
I am sure I can be.
扬起来
Lift it!
前进
Keep moving!
- 拢起来 - 丢上来
- Gather it up! - Hay up!
你去哪
Boy!
保持队形 跟紧
Keep in line! Fall in!
你去干嘛
You there!
前进 跟上
Keep moving! Keep up!
是国王的队伍
There's the King!
- 是国王 - 是玛丽公主和国王
- The King! - Lady Mary and the King!
你瞧 他们多么爱戴我们
You see how much they love us?
他们可是正宗的英格兰人
These are the real people of England.
他们拥戴国君
They love their King.
加德纳主教大人到
His Grace, Bishop Gardiner.
大人 希望没有打扰您
My Lord. I trust I am not disturbing you.
陛下出宫 我深知您重担在肩
I know you bear a heavy burden, in His Majesty's absence.
没有打扰 主教大人 欢迎您的到来
Not at all, Your Grace. You are most welcome.
- 国王那边进展如何 - 好极了
- How goes the King's progress? - Most excellently.
他所到之处
He has been warmly and graciously received.
民众欢声雷动
everywhere he goes.
陛下也满载而归
And he has had good sport.
就在上周 陛下还与其同伴
Just last week he and his companions.
在区区两日内捕获了四百多只鹿
shot over four hundred deer in two days.
此刻他们在回林肯郡途中
They're now on their way to Lincoln.
陛下精神安好 吾甚为高兴
I am very glad to hear His Majesty is in such good spirits.
我想
I suppose…
陛下定会指定萨里伯爵一同前往
he would number among his companions the Earl of Surrey.
当然
Yes, for certain.
- 臣告退 - 为什么
- My Lord. - Why?
我收到一些关于伯爵言行举止的揭发信
I have received more reports of the Earl's behavior.
被封为嘉德勋爵士后
It seems that, after his investiture into the Order of the Garter,
萨里伯爵曾在领土的某个小酒馆内
he appeared in a tavern in his regalia…
公然取笑嘉德勋位及其所有人
and made great fun of the Order and of those belonging to it.
甚至当着鸨母和皮条客的面
Even before bawds and pimps.
这些证词是否确凿
And these are sworn statements of his behavior?
千真万确 大人会深入调查吗
They are, my Lord. Are you going to investigate further?
当然
Yes, I will.
十分感谢大人提供此等重要信息
I am most grateful to Your Grace for this information.
这些信息终有一天会派上用场
I trust that someday you will use it.
我十分确信萨里及其随从
For I am as convinced as I can be that Surrey and his crew.
公然藐视禁食律例
flout the fasting laws.
是狂热的路德派教徒以及圣餐论者
and are fanatic Lutherans and Sacramentarians.
信奉此等异端邪说者
for which damnable heresies.
理应在伦敦肉市场施以火刑示众
they ought to be burned at Smithfield.
大人
Your Grace.
左 左右 左右 左右
Left, left, right, left, right, left, right…
（林肯市教堂）
亨利 承蒙天恩
Henry, by the Grace of God,
作为英格兰 爱尔兰以及法兰西的国王
King of England, Ireland, and France,
更为上帝之宠儿 教会之领袖
also God's high minister here, Head of His Church.
举国之灵魂
and soul of the whole Kingdom.
在此我们虔诚地恳求您
We beseech you in all humility.
赐予人民以活力 治理和拯救世人
to animate, rule, and save your people.
吾等亦向上天祈求 望其仁慈为怀
And we further pray God, of his infinite mercy,
保佑凯瑟琳王后以及玛丽公主
that he will bless and maintain in faith, in love, and in fecundity.
永保信实 关爱与多子多福
Queen Katherine and your blessed daughter, Lady Mary.
阿门
Amen.
陛下
Your Majesty.
林肯郡的子民们
People of Lincoln.
想必在场的诸位一定记得
Do I need to remind you many of you here and about rose up.
尔等非法起义 逆天而行
in an unnatural and unlawful rebellion against your King,
你们理应顺应天意 服从国君
who you, by the laws of God, are bound to obey.
今日吾等齐聚一堂 并不为此
Well, today we come here for an altogether different reason.
而是祈求上帝宽恕
Today we come here on a Pilgrimage of Forgiveness.
吾等聚集此地
We are here.
祈求上帝宽恕汝等既往的罪过与悖逆
to pardon all our subjects for their past sins and disobedience.
尔等之爱戴
And since we have seen how much you love us,
与忠诚展露无余
and seen all your tokens and signs of loyalty,
吾等豁达大度 宽恕你们
with a free heart we forgive you.
此处为陛下寝室
Here is Your Majesty's bedchamber.
那这通向何处
Where does this go?
卫生间
To the Stool Chamber.
那里呢
And that?
通向后楼梯
To the backstairs.
来啊 我想看看
Come on! I want to see.
后面是何处
What's behind here?
国王陛下的寝室
His Majesty's bedchamber.
他的侍从在吗
With his servants?
很糟吧 托马斯
It looks bad, doesn't it, Thomas?
已有所好转 陛下
I have seen it better, Your Majesty.
不过我还是要清洗一下
But I'll bathe it.
今晚我本想临幸王后
I wanted to visit the Queen tonight.
今日在教堂内 她是何等的纯洁美丽
She looked so pure and beautiful in the cathedral today.
你说是吗
Don't you think?
尔等均气度不凡
You were both magnificent.
人民如此仰慕崇拜陛下
And the people adored and worshipped Your Majesty,
此般盛况吾前所未闻
such as I have never seen the like.
陛下是否就寝？
Do you think the King's asleep yet?
他定是晚睡
He must be late.
- 已近午夜 - 他在哪里
- It's almost midnight. - Oh! Where is he?
陛下已就寝
He has gone to sleep.
快召他前来 快点
Go and fetch him. Hurry!
遵命 殿下
Yes, my Lady.
快帮我更衣
Help me change out of this.
- 是谁 - 巡夜的
- Who's that? - The night watchman.
跟上
Come.
我留守此处
I'll stay out here.
我去门口守候
I'll watch outside.
不要在这里
Not in here!
那去哪里
Where then?
这里
In here.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.